# Omar Palau

I'm a UX and technical writing specialist with 7+ years in scrum-driven IT operations and engineering. Experienced in IT architecture analysis, full-stack development, systems administration, and technical support. I'm passionate about driving technology adoption and improving UX.

San Luis Potosi, San Luis Potosi, Mexico, 78290

+52 444 412 2261

omar.palau@outlook.com



**My LinkedIn Profile!** 

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Wizeline**, Mexico (Remote) — Technical Writer

MARCH 2022 - PRESENT

Copywriting, API, and technical documentation for customer-facing apps, in-house software products, and infrastructure migrations.

# **Honeywell**, Mexico (Remote) — Systems Integration Analyst

OCTOBER 2020 - MARCH 2022

Led UX and communications for the IT mobility services creating KBAs, SOPs, communication plans, tutorial videos, and instructional resources.

## **Honeywell,** San Luis Potosi, Mexico — Systems Integration Specialist

JANUARY 2017 - OCTOBER 2020

L2 support, UX research and design, technical writer, service process owner, and web editor. Contributed to 90% of overall service CSAT.

# **Honeywell**, San Luis Potosi, Mexico — *Mobility Digital Native*

JULY 2015 - JANUARY 2017

Approved mobile OS releases via usability testing from the UX standpoint. Tested and certified Honeywell handheld devices for Mobile Device Mgmt.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Universidad TecMilenio, Monterrey, NL, Mexico Master's degree, Information Technology Management

**JULY 2016 - JANUARY 2018** 

With a focus on IT Project Management, specializing in requirements gathering, flow charts, critical path methods (CPM), and project charters.

# Universidad TecMilenio, Toluca, Estado de Mexico, Mexico Bachelor of Engineering in Software Development

AUGUST 2011 - MAY 2015

With a focus on Back-end engineering specializing in the LAMP Stack.

#### **PORTFOLIO**

My work samples!

#### **SKILLS**

IT and Software Information development, video editing, docs-as-code, UX personas, UX journey maps, UML modeling, usability testing, and process/data flows.

#### **TOOLS**

AsciiDoc, Bootstrap 5, Camtasia, Confluence, Figma, GitHub, Grammarly, GSuite, HTML/CSS/JavaScript, Jira, Markdown, Microsoft 365, React.js, Unix CLI.

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**



AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner



Meta Front-End **Developer Certificate** 



**EC-Council Certified Project Management** 

#### **LANGUAGES**

Spanish native, English C1

## **PROJECTS**

# Wizeline (Technical Writer)

## — DevPortal migration

For a fashion retail company, I wrote and peer-reviewed copy texts for 10 software product pages, created and tested sections for code labs, and formatted one year's worth of technology chapters and external events entries in Markdown for a DevPortal. Also, I produced AsciiDoc technical documentation for different software products in a five-month project.

## — AWS migration

For a landscaping company migrating its infrastructure from on-premise to AWS, I created an IT architecture overview, a system administration guide, and a business recovery plan, following the AWS Well-Architected framework in a three-month project.

#### Authentication API

For a media company, I documented the Authentication API reference of their streaming service application, supporting the engineering teams in releasing the user registration and membership enrollment product features in a five-month project.

## **Honeywell (Systems Integration Analyst)**

# — Azure migration

Updated standard operating procedures (SOPs), knowledge base articles (KBAs), and user-facing documentation for an IT service migrating their infrastructure from on-premise to the Azure cloud, resulting in the successful resumption of operations for system administrators and 40,000 users.

## — IT operations insourcing

For the IT mobility team implementing their ITSM operational model, I documented standard operating procedures (SOPs), knowledge base articles (KBAs), and troubleshooting guides. I also onboarded and trained five system administrators to support the team's objectives.

# **Honeywell (Systems Integration Specialist)**

## — Basic to OAuth migration

Created workaround instructions and troubleshooting guides for the IT mobility team's help desk, resulting in a successful migration of 35,000+ end users from Basic to OAuth with a 90% CSAT

#### VMware Boxer Launch

Created setup instructions and how-to videos to assist 2,500 mobile users in adopting the VMware Boxer app for both company and BYOD use for the IT mobility team.

## — Bring Your Own Device (BYOD) program

Designed and developed the web documentation for the IT mobility team Bring Your Own Device (BYOD) service using Bootstrap 3 and successfully coordinated the program's release communications, resulting in the enrollment of 2,500 users.

# — Bootstrap integration to Sharepoint sites

Migrated over 20 user-facing service Sharepoint pages to HTML, CSS, JS, and Bootstrap 3, enhancing the user experience of the IT mobility team's web documentation.

# Honeywell (Mobility Digital Native)

## — Major OS UAT templates

Created user acceptance testing (UAT) templates for the IT mobility team, allowing for the assessment of the service's UX and enabling the IT team to test and approve mobile beta OS releases before launch.

### — Enrollment Guide Modernization

Simplified the mobile activation instructions for the IT mobility service's device request and enrollment process, reducing 25 PDF pages to a 5-minute read article and a 3-minute how-to video.

# Universidad TecMilenio (Back-end developer Intern)

# — Incident Management Portal

For a government financial office, I developed a PHP-based Incident Management application that enabled their technical support team to efficiently track and manage reported issues and their resolutions.

## — Configuration Management Data Base

I developed a PHP application for an IT services company to manage employee records and associate their computing and information resources, supporting the company's ITIL configuration management strategy.